# AHMAD DIDIK SETIYADI

Semarang, Indonesia | adidiksetiyadi@gmail.com | +62 82227833820 https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmaddidiks | https://github.com/ahmaddidiks

#### **OBJECTIVE**

I am an Embedded Software Engineer with 2 years' experience in developing cutting edge embedded systems. I have skills in C, C++ and Python, especially in **embedded systems**. I am experienced in optimizing **embedded Linux** and **RTOS** systems which interact with sensors and actuators.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Abarobotics | Semarang, Indonesia

# **Embedded Software Team Lead (Nov 2022 - present)**

- Managing embedded people for working on several projects and research
- Developing mobile robot guide in Hospital with NAV2 ROS2 based
- Optimized 80% CPU resource efficiency in embedded Linux automatic parking gate with RFID and LPR (License Plate Recognition)
- Developed embedded Linux automatic attendance smart meeting monitor with NFC and face recognition
- Developed embedded hardware watchdog for monitoring existing project with Espressif chip based

# Abarobotics | Semarang, Indonesia

### **Embedded Software Engineer** (Dec 2021 – Nov 2022)

- Developed low level control system for automatic excavator robot with RTOS
- Developed automatic medicine pills sorted with RTOS
- Tested and documented on embedded Linux automatic parking gate with RFID system.

# Digitels | Remote

# **IoT Firmware Engineer** (Sept 2022 – Feb 2023)

- Optimized existing embedded code for gaining efficiency and decreasing memory consumption around 30%
- Worked on multiple communication such as Wi-Fi and LoRa

# Skilvul | Remote

### IoT Mentor SIC (Samsung Innovation Campus) 4 (April 2023 – present)

- Mentored IoT bootcamp for building hardware and software of selected mentee's idea
- Mentored Python class for IoT bootcamp preparation.

### Skilvul | Remote, Indonesia

### **IoT Mentor SIC (Samsung Innovation Campus) 3** (June 2022 – Sept 2022)

- Selected to be the 3 best mentors of 9 mentors
- Mentored IoT bootcamp for building hardware and software of selected mentee's idea,

Redesma Technologies | Semarang, Indonesia

**Embedded Software Engineer (**Feb 2021 – July 2021)

- Developed automatic oil tank leveling with lidar sensor
- Developed blood shaker prototype with PID controller.

#### **EDUCATION**

Diponegoro University | Semarang, Indonesia

Electrical Engineering, Robotics | GPA 3.60 of 4.0 (2017-2021)

Thesis: 4 DOF Manipulator Robot with Inverse Kinematics and Trajectory Planning Using Robot Operating System (ROS)

Achievements:

- 3<sup>rd</sup> Runner Up Indonesian Humanoid Soccer Robot Competition Regional 1 (2020)
- 4<sup>th</sup> Runner Up UNNES University National Paper Competition (2019)
- 3<sup>rd</sup> Runner Up Indonesian Humanoid Soccer Robot Competition Regional 3 (2019)
- Bronze medal Thailand Inventor's Day (2019)
- 2<sup>nd</sup> Gajah Mada University Soccer Robot Competition (2018)

# LEADERSHIP ACTIVITIES

Ews Bascorro | Semarang, Indonesia

**Team Lead** (Aug 2019 – Sept 2020)

- Managed humanoid soccer robot university team to build completely new robot with ROS based
- Developed robot movement gait and algorithms
- Migrated robot strategy algorithms code from AVR MCU based into ROS.

Ews Bascorro | Semarang, Indonesia

Motion Planner (Aug 2018 – Aug 2019)

Developed robot movement gait

**Engineering Study Forum** | Semarang, Indonesia

**Research Division Member** (Feb 2018-Jan 2019)

Contributed to research-based activity, learning strategy, and competition in Engineering Faculty

### **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

**Technical:** Bash, C, C++, Python, Embedded Linux, RTOS

**Interests:** Optimizing embedded Linux performance and memory with battery efficiency and resources constrain.